# DAMILOLA IBIKUNLE

# SENIOR SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

I am a senior scientific officer with more than 5 years of experience in research and development within space and satellite technologies.

I also have over 3 years of professional experience in customer care service and an educational background in Information Security and computer science.

## **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

- Python for Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Microsoft Excel
- MySQL
- Git
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap5

### OTHER SKILLS

- Research Skills
- Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Data Security
- Customer Relationship management
- Project Management
- Risk Assessment

### **EXPERIENCE**

# SENIOR SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

National Space Research and Development Agency (NASRDA)

Jan 2023 - Present

- Responsible for overseeing and managing the instrumentation team within the spacecraft aerodynamics and control department
- Ensuring accurate and adequate measurement and application of all data/apparatus used for a successful satellite design and mission life.
- Member of the team assigned to design and develop customizable Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) tailored for specific purposes.
- Conduct independent research on Space and Satellite Technologies.
- Active member of the Training and Technical Committee within the Nigerian Institute of Space Engineers (NISEng).

## SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

National Space Research and Development Agency (NASRDA)

Aug 2018 - Dec 2022.

- Conducted independent and extensive research on control systems for Space and Satellite Technologies.
- Was a member of the embedded systems team responsible for designing and developing space equipment, including Unmanned Ground Vehicles (UGVs) and Deep Space Antenna Trackers.

### CUSTOMER CARE REPRESENTATIVE

Globacom Limited (GLO) Jan 2015 - July 2018

- Provided customers with accurate information about the company's products and services in response to their inquiries.
- Addressed and resolving customer account issues, and escalated them to the relevant channels when required.
- Efficiently updated and maintained customer account information using a variety of company applications while exhibiting strong multitasking abilities.
- Created service requests for each customer to facilitate the preparation of comprehensive product and services reports for company analysis.
- Assisted in sales efforts by advising and educating customers about new products and services introduced by the company.

# INTERNSHIP - NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC)

SHELL PETROLEUM DEVELOPMENT COMPANY OF NIGERIA - (SPDC ABUJA)
Jul 2011 - Jul 2012

- Offered infrastructure and IT support services.
- Managed and organized records and manifests for visiting staff and guests.
- Assisted the welfare committee with various company events, including the annual Shell University Scholarship Scheme in Abuja.

### **EDUCATION**

# MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.SC)

Information Security

University of Salford Manchester | Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

# BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.SC)

Computer Science

University of Lagos Akoka | Sept 2006 - Dec 2010

## CERTIFICATIONS

# IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

IBM Skills Network

Jun 27, 2023

# CERTIFIED ETHICAL HACKER V9 (CEH)

EC-Council

Certification N0: ECC614097258

Nov 19, 2018 - Nov 18, 2021

### CONTACT



https://damiieibikun.github.io/



https://github.com/Damiieibikun



damiieibikun@gmail.com



Abuja Nigeria